Like a fairy tale
It's a sign the story has reached its end
Like a single passage taken from
A journey that was too long
Of the evil that once cast a shadow
Across this land
And the memories of the short journey
With the hero who defeated it
The story ends
And the hero goes to sleep
Leaving this land with
Days of peace and quiet
The passage of time heartlessly
Makes people forget
Even the tracks left behind by his life
Begin to rust
Just the same
Your words and wishes and courage
Are still inside of me
And they live on
We chose the same path
That's all it was supposed to be
Why is it that at some point
I wanted to understand the reason for
The tears that fall down my cheeks
Even now
If I retrace the journey we walked together
Even though you're not there
I know I'll be able to find it
How long have you been traveling together?
Um...
I first embarked on my journey with
Ms. Frieren about four years ago.
It's been about a year for me.
I see.
There's something this party lacks.
What do you think that is?
We've got a front-liner, mages, and a priest.
A thief, perhaps?
Since Ms. Frieren is always
falling for mimics.
Aw, yeah.
Oh, come on.
Treasure chests contain unlimited potential.
No.
What we lack is something
even more important.
An older lady!
Most parties have at least
one sexy older lady!
Do they?
But we've got Frieren.
No. She's not an older lady.
He looks so distraught.
Sorry about that.
H-Hey, the next village is coming into view.
They're breathing.
Same over here.
What's going on here? Everyone's asleep.
This smells like trouble.
Let's head to the next village.
Don't make me angry, Ms. Frieren.
I'm just kidding.
It's a curse.
I thought so. What a hassle.
Hey, Frieren. What are curses?
Among the spells cast by monsters and demons
are those that put people to sleep
or turn them to stone.
Those which humankind has yet
to unravel are known as curses.
Humanity's magic can't explain the principles
behind them or how to remove them.
Does that mean it's too late for this village?
I'm only talking about humanity's magic.
The magic of the Goddess,
which priests use, is a different story.
Tackling curses has long been
the business of the clergy.
Well, Sein? Think you can help them?
Don't rush me.
I'm currently determining the
type and source of the curse.
How is the magic of the Goddess
different from other magic?
The magic of the Goddess
is recorded in holy scriptures
and can only be used by
the owners of said scriptures.
Like the demons' magic, we don't understand
the principles behind most of it,
so it's not very interesting.
And it's difficult to use unless you're born
with the specific knack for it,
which also bestows an
increased resistance to curses.
I believe they call it
"the blessing of the Goddess."
Anyway, that's why priests
are strong against curses.
So not even you can effectively
defend against curses?
Mages can't detect curses.
I can sense I'm being attacked in some way,
so I know this village is still under
the effects of the curse.
I feel anxious.
Does that mean we're actively
being cursed? I'm scared!
I've determined that it's
a rather unusual curse.
You can't remove it?
I'd need tools to conduct
a specialized ritual.
It'd be faster to defeat
the source of the curse.
It's coming from a monster.
I've determined its location.
Let's go.
That'll save time.
Ms. Frieren.
It's Mr. Stark.
He's asleep.
Can you wake him temporarily?
With my current abilities, five seconds
is the longest I can keep him awake.
That's practically nothing.
In any case, it looks like we should hurry.
Fern won't wake up.
She said she was just taking a little break.
So Fern has fallen asleep, too.
This is starting to look bad.
I put up a barrier.
We'll hide them in here.
We're almost there. I can tell it's close.
I see.
Sein, wake me when the monster shows up.
Don't fight it alone.
I promise I'll defeat it.
I told you, five seconds
is the longest I can...
Frieren?
We can't do anything with five seconds.
Fine.
I have battle magic, too.
It's a subspecies of chaos flower.
It must be feeding off
the sleeping villagers.
It'll sap away their mana
until it eventually kills them.
Chaos flowers merge with the
local flora to create subspecies.
It's like a mirror.
But no matter what they look like,
their weakness is always their core.
Three Spears of the Goddess!
What happened?
Did it reflect my magic?
Unless I score a direct hit on the core,
the leaves could deflect
my spells in any direction.
If I'm not careful, it could hit Frieren.
Damn it. This can only get worse.
Should I wake Frieren?
But she's the mage from the party of heroes.
If a powerful spell were deflected,
it could destroy not just the forest,
but the village, too.
It's just five seconds.
That's not enough time to explain.
And Frieren and I haven't had the time
to establish a mutual understanding
or learn to trust each other.
I don't even know what Frieren's thinking.
That's right.
I never know what she's thinking.
I don't believe adventurers require
mutual understanding or trust.
My companion Frieren was
especially terrible at both.
So I decided to trust her words.
She swore she would defeat the Demon King,
and I chose to believe her.
Trust her words, huh?
Don't fight it alone.
I promise I'll defeat it.
She looked like a mess.
Don't blame me for whatever happens!
Awakening spell!
Frieren, only the core—
Got it.
What's going on here?
Thank you.
I won't forget this.
We didn't do much.
No.
I've never been happier to be
awakened, thanks to you.
The moment I woke up, I knew that it
was the kind that reflects magic.
You really are an incredible mage.
But we made it out alive
because of you, Sein.
Thanks.
Good boy.
That lady from the village sure was pretty.
You're still saying that?
That's Vorig?
It's the relay point to Äußerst.
We're finally halfway there?
This really is a long journey.
We'll resupply in Vorig, and—
Ms. Frieren, this is awkward,
but we're nearly out of funds.
Hey, you.
What is it?
That's a noble's carriage.
Huh?
What? What's going on?
You've got a nice body.
Your appearance isn't too bad either.
Come to my mansion.
What's going on?
What's your name?
Stark.
Lord Orden, you can't do this.
You know who I am?
This is the mansion of the Orden family,
one of the Three Great Families
of the northern lands.
Your grandfather was a high-handed man, too.
What is this nonsense?
Either way, I'm having a conversation
with Stark right now.
He's my party's front-liner.
Stark, do you need your mommy's
permission to have a conversation?
Please don't fight.
I have a request. I'll pay you.
This is ridiculous. We're leaving, Stark.
Ms. Frieren.
What are those copper coins?
They're all the funds we have left.
I guess we can at least hear you out.
Frieren...
Stark, where are you from?
A warrior village in the Klee region
of the central lands.
I see. My family line is originally
from that village, too.
My eldest son, Wirt.
My heir and hero of this city.
He looks like you, Mr. Stark.
You're practically identical.
If we got you cleaned up,
only someone from within the family
would be able to tell the difference.
What does that have to do with your request?
A month ago, we fought a
large battle against demons.
Wirt died in action.
He and the enemy commander
killed each other.
The silver lining was that
it was a large-scale melee.
The only ones who know of Wirt's death
are Gabel over there
and a few of my most trusted men.
What are you planning to make Stark do?
The fortress city of Vorig is key
to this region's defense.
We can't allow morale to fall while
we're rebuilding the forces we lost.
So you want to cover up
your son's death until then.
Three months from now, this region's
influential figures will meet at a soirée.
We'll show them that Wirt is alive and well.
How much will you pay us?
Ten Strahl gold coins.
That's three meals a day
plus snacks for a year.
Throw in a grimoire.
You can take one of your
choosing from the library.
Hold on. I can't do this.
What am I gonna do about
this scar on my forehead?
The people already believe
Wirt is recuperating.
That's an honorable battle scar.
Mr. Stark, we need the money.
This is sad.
Gabel, teach Stark proper etiquette.
Mr. Stark, how is your etiquette
training coming along?
It's hell.
What do you think?
It doesn't suit you.
That's not nice.
I'm gonna get some fresh air.
Lord Orden.
Aren't I always telling you
to call me "Father"?
You never know when someone
might be watching.
Aren't you being too cold?
It's been less than two months
since your son died.
I'm simply following my son's final wishes.
I even had a double prepared.
He didn't look as much like him
as you do, though.
I can't say I enjoy this.
But it's what my son wanted.
I'll need your cooperation.
You're so awkward.
Mut, stand up taller.
Yes, Father.
My second son, Mut.
He's to be my heir, but he
shows little improvement.
But by contrast, Stark is a failure.
Skill with a sword affects one's posture.
I'll teach you the Orden family technique.
What's wrong?
It's all right. Take deep breaths.
This isn't your village.
Lord Orden, what do you think of Mut?
He doesn't have his brother's talent.
But he's a hard worker.
What he's worked to build up
won't let him down.
Someday he'll become
a stronger knight than me.
I see.
You should tell that to Mut.
I do.
But it's gone to his head,
so he doesn't improve.
Now that's a problem.
What?
I have to learn etiquette, too?
It's a soirée.
You expect a young man to attend it alone?
Or will his mommy escort him instead?
Good luck.
This past month has been hell.
We need the money, right?
I'm sorry.
We practiced. We might as well dance.
That really doesn't suit you.
Shall we dance as well?
I'm going to eat cake.
I see.
If not for this injury,
I would've been in the vanguard.
Perhaps then, Wirt wouldn't have died.
Milord...
Looks like the soirée is over.
You've completed the job.
Gabel, give Frieren her reward.
Stark, you're an incredibly
powerful warrior.
If you'd like—
I can't replace your son.
You're right.
And I can't replace your father.
But you don't have a home to return to.
The warrior village of the Klee region
was destroyed by demons.
I know that much.
My son and I parted in anger.
We got into an argument
over something trivial.
I told him I never wanted
to see his face again.
I didn't mean it.
When I found you,
I thought it was a miracle.
All the more reason I can't stay here.
I said something I didn't mean, too,
to the man who raised me.
So I have to bring him back
stories of my travels.
I see.
Which grimoire should
I choose for my reward?
Ms. Frieren, it's been half a day.
You're distressing Mr. Gabel.
Please hurry up.
Look. All the life has left him.
It'll be some time until
they rebuild their forces.
What is it?
Nothing.
At the very least, he won't
have to worry about his heir.
A forgotten hero, huh?
He's a forgotten hero.
No one even knows his name.
He's totally decrepit.
He's been alone this whole time.
Humans grow quickly.
He's a long-lived friend of mine.